## Inspiration
At first we looked at the most serious and dangerous problems in Hajj and then decided that the congestion between the pilgrims and defenders are one of the most common problems facing by pilgrims and the organizers . For example : On 24 September 2015 an event described as a "crush and stampede" caused deaths estimated at well over 2,000 pilgrims, suffocated or crushed during the annual Hajj pilgrimage in Mina, Mecca, Saudi Arabia. From this we concluded that congestion is the most serious problem for the life of the pilgrim. 

## What it does
This project uses artificial intelligence to analyze crowd images taken by cameras on ways from/to Macha’er and calculate the density, distances between the pilgrims and speed and then be processed and issued a decision in cases of congestion and critical situations through the status of helping decisions through presentation on maps: arrows, colors, emoticons (for pilgrims users interface)  .
 With this data, we can give a decision helping to the Security Police and pilgrims, to aware them.

## How we built it
We get images from cameras situated in ways to/from Macha’er, doing image processing and artificial intelligence to detect their direction, density, and so we can know the most dangerous regions.


## Challenges we ran into
Analyze a huge number of data

## Accomplishments that we're proud of
We have come up with an idea that can be applied and written programmatically and helps more than one user: Hajj and government agencies.

## What we learned
This application teaches us how to know pilgrims what are the crowded and non-crowded for using artificial intelligence and the use of expressive graphics (Emoji) that facilitate the knowledge of crowding before entering the place of crowding.

## What's next for Hajj Crowd 
If this program actually succeeds in the application, we will apply it to public places of crowding.
